♪ (OMINOUS MUSIC PLAYS) ♪
（不祥的音乐剧）
TYRION LANNISTER: Cersei's followers will abandon her
提利昂·兰尼斯特：塞西 追随者会抛弃她
if they know the war is lost.
如果他们知道战争失败了。
Give them that chance.
给他们这个机会。
If the city surrenders,
如果城市投降，
they will ring the bells and raise the gates.
他们会敲响警钟 升起大门。
(BELLS RING)
（钟声响起）
(PANTING)
（喘气）
(RINGING INTENSIFIES)
（阻尼振荡intensifies）
(DISTANT SCREAMING)
（远处的尖叫声）
♪ (MUSIC CONTINUES) ♪
（音乐继续）
[♪♪♪]
[谚]
I'll find you later.
我稍后再找你。
It's not safe.
这不安全。
Let me send some men with you.
让我派几个人和你一起去。
I'm going alone.
我一个人去。
In the name of the one true queen,
以名字 一个真正的皇后，
Daenerys Targaryen,
丹妮莉丝·塔格利安，
I sentence you to die.
我判你死刑。
JON: Grey Worm!
乔恩： 灰虫！
It's over.
结束了。
These men are prisoners.
这些人是囚犯。
It is not over until the queen's enemies are defeated.
直到女王的婚礼才结束 敌人被打败了。
How much more defeated do you want them to be?
还有多少失败 你想让他们成为吗？
- They're on their knees. - They are breathing.
-他们跪着。 -他们在呼吸。
Look around you, friend. We won.
看看你周围，朋友。我们赢了。
I obey my queen's commands, not yours.
我服从女王的命令， 不是你的。
JON: And what are the queen's commands?
乔恩： 女王的命令是什么？
"Kill all who follow Cersei Lannister."
“杀死所有跟随的人 塞西·兰尼斯特。”
These are free men.
他们是自由人。
They chose to fight for her.
他们选择为她而战。
DAVOS: Easy, men. Easy! Easy.
达沃斯： 轻松，伙计们。容易的！容易的。
Jon.
乔恩。
We should speak with the queen.
我们应该和女王谈谈。
[GRUNTS SOFTLY]
温柔的[人]
[♪♪♪]
[谚]
[PANTING SOFTLY]
[轻轻喘气]
[CRYING]
[哭泣]
[SNIFFLES]
[Sinfles]
[DOTHRAKI SHOUTING INDISTINCTLY]
[多斯拉克大喊 隐晦地
[HORSES NEIGHING]
[马嘶鸣]
Hyah!
啊哈！
[♪♪♪]
[谚]
[DROGON ROARS]
[德罗贡咆哮]
[SIGHS]
[叹息]
[DROGON ROARING] [DOTHRAKI CHEERING]
[Drogon咆哮] [多斯拉克欢呼声]
[♪♪♪]
[谚]
[CHEERING WILDLY]
[疯狂欢呼]
[IN DOTHRAKI]
[多斯拉克]
[DOTHRAKI CHEERING]
[多斯拉克欢呼声]
[ROARING]
[咆哮]
Torgo Nudho.
Torgo Nudho。
[IN VALYRIAN]
[在]亚
[SPEARS THUMPING]
[长矛重击]
[DROGON ROARS]
[德罗贡咆哮]
[DOTHRAKI CHEERING]
[多斯拉克欢呼声]
[♪♪♪]
[谚]
[SIGHS]
[叹息]
[DROGON ROARS]
[德罗贡咆哮]
[IN ENGLISH] You freed your brother.
[英语] 你释放了你弟弟。
You committed treason.
你犯了叛国罪。
I freed my brother.
我释放了我弟弟。
And you slaughtered a city.
你屠杀了一座城市。
[IN VALYRIAN]
[在]亚
[♪♪♪]
[谚]
What are you doing here?
你在这里干什么？
Hey, what happened?
嘿，怎么了？
I came to kill Cersei.
我是来杀瑟曦的。
Your queen got there first.
你的王后先到那里。
[SIGHS]
[叹息]
JON: She's everyone's queen now.
乔恩： 她现在是每个人的女王了。
Try telling Sansa.
试着告诉桑萨。
Wait for me outside the city gates.
等我 在城门外。
- I'll come find you. - Jon.
-我来找你。 乔恩。
She knows who you are.
她知道你是谁。
Who you really are.
你到底是谁。
You'll always be a threat to her.
你将永远 对她构成威胁。
And I know a killer when I see one.
我认识一个杀手 当我看到一个。
[DOOR CLOSES]
[关门]
Did you bring any wine?
你带了酒吗？
No.
不。
Ah...
啊…
Well...
好。。。
thank you for coming to see me.
谢谢你来 来见我。
Our queen doesn't keep prisoners for long.
我们的女王不关押囚犯 很长时间。
I suppose there's a crude kind of justice.
我想有 一种粗糙的正义。
I betrayed my closest friend and watched him burn.
我背叛了我最亲密的朋友 看着他燃烧。
Now Varys's ashes can tell my ashes:
现在瓦里斯的骨灰 可以告诉我的骨灰：
"See, I told you."
“你看，我告诉过你的。”
It just occurred to me.
我刚刚想到。
I'm talking to the only man alive
我在说 给唯一活着的人
who knows where I'm going.
谁知道我要去哪里。
[SIGHS]
[叹息]
So is there life after death?
死后还有生命吗？
Not that I've seen.
不是我见过的。
I should be thankful.
我应该感谢你。
Oblivion is the best I could hope for.
遗忘是最好的 我希望如此。
I strangled my lover.
我勒死了我的爱人。
I shot my own father with a crossbow.
我杀了我自己的父亲 用十字弓。
I betrayed my queen.
我背叛了我的女王。
- You didn't. - I did.
-你没有。 -是的。
And I'd do it again,
我会再做一次，
now that I've seen what I've seen.
现在我看到了 我看到了什么。
I chose my fate.
我选择了我的命运。
The people of King's Landing did not.
人民 国王的登陆没有。
I can't justify what happened.
我不能证明发生了什么。
I won't try.
我不会尝试的。
- But the war is over now. - Is it?
-但是战争现在结束了。 -是吗？
When you heard her talking to her soldiers,
当你听到她 和她的士兵交谈，
did she sound like someone who's done fighting?
她听起来像人吗 谁打架了？
She liberated the people of Slaver's Bay.
她解放了人民 斯莱弗湾。
of King's Landing.
国王的登陆。
And she'll go on liberating
她会继续解放
until the people of the world are free...
直到世界人民 是免费的…
and she rules them all.
她统领着他们。
And you've been by her side, counseling her.
你一直在她身边， 辅导她。
Until today.
直到今天。
[SOFTLY]
[温柔地]
Varys was right.
瓦里斯是对的。
I was wrong.
我错了。
It was vanity to think I could guide her.
这是虚荣 以为我能引导她。
Our queen's nature is fire and blood.
我们女王的本性 是血与火。
You think our house words are stamped on our bodies
你认为我们家的话 印在我们身上
when we're born and that's who we are?
当我们出生的时候 我们就是这样？
Then I'd be fire and blood too.
那我也会是火和血。
She's not her father,
她不是她父亲，
no more than you're Tywin Lannister.
不超过 你是泰温·兰尼斯特。
My father was an evil man. My sister was an evil woman.
我父亲是个坏人。 我妹妹是个邪恶的女人。
Pile up all the bodies
把尸体堆起来
of all the people they ever killed,
在所有人中 他们曾经杀过，
there still won't be half as many
还是不会有 一半那么多
as our beautiful queen slaughtered in a single day.
作为我们美丽的女王 在一天内被屠宰。
Cersei left her no choice.
瑟曦别无选择。
The moment the gates fell,
门一掉下来，
the battle was over.
战斗结束了。
She saw her friend beheaded.
她看见她的朋友被斩首了。
She saw her dragon shot out of the sky.
她看到了她的龙 从天空中射出。
And she burned down a city for it.
她被烧死了 一个适合它的城市。
Ah, it's easy to judge when you're standing
啊，很容易判断 当你站着的时候
far from the battlefield.
远离战场。
Would you have done it?
你会这样做吗？
What?
什么？
You've been up there, on a dragon's back.
你去过那里， 在龙的背上。
You've had that power.
你有这种能力。
Would you have burned the city down?
你会烧了吗 这座城市倒塌了吗？
- I don't know. - [SCOFFS]
-我不知道。 你嘲笑[ ]
Yes, you do.
是的，你知道。
You won't say because you don't want to betray her...
你不会说因为 你不想背叛她…
but you know.
但你知道。
What's it matter what I'd do?
我会怎么做有什么关系？
It matters more than anything.
这比任何事都重要。
When she murdered the slavers of Astapor,
当她被谋杀时 阿斯塔波尔的奴隶，
I'm sure no one but the slavers complained.
我肯定没有人 但是奴隶主抱怨。
After all, they were evil men.
毕竟，他们是邪恶的人。
[SIGHS]
[叹息]
When she crucified hundreds of Meereenese nobles,
当她把数百人钉在十字架上时 来自高贵的弥林
who could argue?
谁能争论？
They were evil men.
他们是坏人。
The Dothraki khals she burned alive?
多斯拉克卡其布 她活活烧死了？
They would have done worse to her.
他们会 对她不利。
Everywhere she goes, evil men die
无论她走到哪里， 坏人死了
and we cheer her for it.
我们为她欢呼。
And she grows more powerful
她变得更强大了
and more sure that she is good and right.
更加确信 她是个好人。
She believes her destiny
她相信自己的命运
is to build a better world for everyone.
就是要建设一个更好的世界 对每个人来说。
If you believed that...
如果你相信…
if you truly believed it,
如果你真的相信，
wouldn't you kill
你不会杀人吗？
whoever stood between you and paradise?
站在中间的人 你和天堂？
[JON INHALES DEEPLY]
[乔恩深深地吸气]
I know you love her.
我知道你爱她。
I love her too.
我也爱她。
Not as successfully as you.
不如你成功。
But I believed in her with all my heart.
但我相信她 全心全意。
Love is more powerful than reason.
爱情更强大 比理智更重要。
[SNIFFLES]
[Sinfles]
We all know that.
我们都知道。
Look at my brother.
看看我哥哥。
"Love is the death of duty."
“爱是责任的死亡。”
[SNIFFLES]
[Sinfles]
You just came up with that?
你刚想到这个？
Maester Aemon said it a long time ago.
艾蒙大师说 很久以前。
Sometimes duty is the death of love.
有时 责任是爱的死亡。
[SNIFFLES]
[Sinfles]
You are the shield that guards the realms of men.
你是盾牌 守卫着人类的领地。
And you've always tried to do the right thing.
你一直在尝试 做正确的事。
No matter the cost,
不管代价如何，
you've tried to protect people.
你试图保护人们。
Who is the greatest threat to the people now?
谁是最大的威胁 *的人吗？
It's a terrible thing I'm asking.
这是件可怕的事 我在问。
It's also the right thing.
这也是正确的。
Do you think I'm the last man she'll execute?
你认为我是最后一个男人吗 她会执行吗？
Who is more dangerous
谁更危险
than the rightful heir to the Iron Throne?
比合法继承人 去铁王座？
[EXHALES SHAKILY]
[呼出颤抖]
That's her decision. She is the queen.
这是她的决定。 她是女王。
I'm sorry it came to this.
很抱歉，事情是这样的。
[KNOCKS ON DOOR]
[敲门]
And your sisters?
你的姐妹们呢？
Do you see them bending the knee?
你看见他们了吗？ 弯曲膝盖？
[FOOTSTEPS APPROACHING]
[脚步声接近]
My sisters will be loyal to the throne.
我的姐妹会忠诚的 登上王位
Why do you think Sansa told me the truth about you?
你为什么认为桑萨 告诉我关于你的真相？
Because she doesn't want Dany to be queen.
因为她不想要丹尼 成为女王。
- She doesn't get to choose. - No.
-她不能选择。 -没有。
But you do.
但你知道。
[KEY RATTLING]
rattling [密码]
And you have to choose now.
现在你必须做出选择。
[♪♪♪]
[谚]
[GROWLS SOFTLY]
[轻轻地咆哮]
[WOMAN VOCALIZING]
♪♪[女人发声]
[♪♪♪]
[谚]
When I was a girl, my brother told me it was made
当我还是个女孩的时候， 我哥哥告诉我它是造的
with 1000 swords from Aegon's fallen enemies.
用1000把剑 Aegon陷阱和敌人。
What do 1000 swords look like
1000把剑是什么样子的
in the mind of a little girl who can't count to 20?
在一个小女孩的脑海里 谁不能数到20？
I imagined a mountain of swords too high to climb.
我想象着一座剑山 爬得太高了。
So many fallen enemies,
这么多倒下的敌人，
you could only see the soles of Aegon's feet.
你只能看到 埃贡的脚底。
JON: I saw them executing
乔恩： 我看到他们行刑
Lannister prisoners in the street.
兰尼斯特囚犯 在街上。
They said they were acting on your orders.
他们说他们在演戏 根据你的命令。
- It was necessary. - Necessary?
-这是必要的。 你有必要吗？
Have you been down there?
你去过那里吗？
Have you seen?
你看见了吗？
Children, little children, burned!
孩子们， 孩子们，被烧死了！
I tried to make peace with Cersei.
我试图使和平 和Cersei在一起。
She used their innocence as a weapon against me.
她利用他们的纯真 作为对抗我的武器。
She thought it would cripple me.
她认为 它会使我残废。
And Tyrion?
提利昂的鸭子吗？
He conspired behind my back with my enemies.
他在我背后密谋 和我的敌人在一起。
How have you treated people who've done the same to you,
你怎么对待别人 对你做过同样的事，
even when it broke your heart?
即使当它摧毁了你的心？
Forgive him.
原谅他。
- I can't. - You can.
-我不能。 你可以。
You can forgive all of them,
你可以原谅他们，
make them see they made a mistake.
让他们看到 他们犯了一个错误。
Make them understand.
让他们明白。
Please, Dany.
求求你，Dany。
We can't hide behind small mercies.
我们不能躲在后面 小怜悯
The world we need
我们需要的世界
won't be built by men loyal to the world we have.
不会由男人建造的 忠于我们所拥有的世界。
The world we need is a world of mercy. It has to be.
我们需要的世界是一个世界 仁慈的必须这样。
And it will be.
它将是。
It's not easy to see something that's never been before.
看东西不容易 这是前所未有的。
[♪♪♪]
[谚]
A good world.
一个美好的世界。
How do you know?
你怎么知道的？
How do you know it'll be good?
你怎么知道会好起来？
Because I know what is good.
因为我知道什么是好的。
And so do you.
你也一样。
- I don't. - You do.
-我没有。 -是的。
You do. You've always known.
是的。你一直都知道。
What about everyone else?
其他人呢？
All the other people who think they know what's good.
所有其他人 他们认为自己知道什么是好的。
They don't get to choose.
他们不能选择。
Be with me.
和我在一起。
Build the new world with me.
和我一起建设新世界。
This is our reason.
这就是我们的原因。
It has been from the beginning,
它已经被 从一开始，
since you were a little boy with a bastard's name
从你小时候起 有个混蛋的名字
and I was a little girl who couldn't count to 20.
我还是个小女孩 数到20。
We do it together.
我们一起做。
[SOFTLY] We break the wheel together.
[温柔地] 我们一起打破车轮。
You are my queen.
你是我的女王。
Now, and always.
现在，永远。
[♪♪♪]
[谚]
[GRUNTS]
[咕噜]
[BOTH PANTING]
[气喘吁吁]
[GASPING SOFTLY]
[轻轻地喘气]
[EXHALES]
【exhales ]
[EXHALES SHARPLY]
【exhales sharply ]
[CRYING]
[哭泣]
[♪♪♪]
[谚]
[DROGON GROWLING]
[Drogon咆哮]
[GROWLING]
[咆哮]
[SNIFFS]
[嗅探]
[♪♪♪]
[谚]
[WINGS FLAPPING]
[ ]翅膀拍打
[FOOTSTEPS APPROACHING]
[脚步声接近]
Where's Jon?
乔恩在哪里？
He is our prisoner. SANSA: So is Lord Tyrion.
他是我们的囚犯。 桑萨：提利昂勋爵也是。
They were both to be brought to this gathering.
他们两个都要带来 参加这次聚会。
We will decide what we do with our prisoners.
我们会决定我们做什么 和我们的囚犯。
This is our city now.
这是我们的城市。
If you look outside the walls of your city,
如果你看墙外 你的城市，
you'll find thousands of Northmen
你会发现成千上万 北方人
who will explain to you why harming Jon Snow
谁来给你解释 为什么要伤害乔恩·斯诺
is not in your interest.
不符合你的利益。
And you will find thousands of Unsullied
你会发现 成千上万的无污染
who believe that it is.
谁相信这是真的？
Some of you may be quick to forgive.
你们中的一些人可能 很快原谅。
The Ironborn are not.
铁人不是。
I swore to follow Daenerys Targaryen.
我发誓要遵守 丹妮莉丝·塔格利安。
You swore to follow a tyrant.
你发誓要追随暴君。
She freed us from a tyrant.
她把我们从暴君手中解放了出来。
Cersei is gone because of her,
瑟曦因为她走了，
and Jon Snow put a knife in her heart.
乔恩·斯诺放了把刀 在她的心中。
Let the Unsullied give him what he deserves.
让没有污染的人给他 他应得的。
Say another word about killing my brother
再说一句话 关于杀了我弟弟
and I'll cut your throat.
我会割破你的喉咙。
Friends, please.
朋友们，拜托。
We've been cutting each other's throats long enough.
我们一直在切对方的 喉咙足够长。
Torgo Nudho. Am I saying that properly?
Torgo Nudho。 我说得对吗？
If it weren't for you and your men,
如果不是你的话 还有你们的人，
we would've lost the war with the dead.
我们会输掉战争的 与死者同在。
This country owes you a debt it can never repay,
这个国家欠你的 无法偿还的债务，
but let us try.
但是让我们试试。
There is land in the Reach.
触手可及的是陆地。
Good land.
好土地。
The people that used to live there are gone.
曾经生活过的人 已经过去了。
Make it your own. Start your own house
自己动手吧。 开你自己的家
with the Unsullied as your bannermen.
与无污染的 作为你的旗帜。
We've had enough war.
我们已经打够了。
Thousands of you, thousands of them.
成千上万的人， 成千上万的人。
You know how it ends.
你知道它是怎么结束的。
We need to find a better way.
我们需要找到更好的方法。
We do not need payment.
我们不需要付款。
We need justice.
我们需要正义。
Jon Snow cannot go free.
乔恩·斯诺不能自由。
It's not for you to decide.
不是你自己决定的。
You are not here to speak!
你不是来说话的！
Everyone has heard enough words from you.
每个人都听够了 从你。
You're right.
你说得对。
And no one's any better for it.
没有人比这更好了。
But it's not for you to decide.
但这不是由你决定的。
Jon committed his crime here.
乔恩在这里犯了罪。
His fate is for our king to decide.
他的命运 由国王决定。
Or our queen.
或者是我们的女王。
We don't have a king or queen.
我们没有国王或王后。
You're the most powerful people in Westeros.
你是最有权势的人 在Westeros。
Choose one.
选择一个。
Make your choice, then.
那就做你的选择吧。
My lords and ladies...
大人女士们…
[CLEARS THROAT]
[清喉咙]
I suppose this is the most important moment of our lives.
我想这是最 我们生命中的重要时刻。
What we decide today will reverberate
我们今天的决定 会回响
through the annals of history.
通过历史的编年史。
I stand before you
我站在你面前
as one of the senior lords in the country.
作为高级领主之一 在乡下。
A veteran of two wars.
两场战争的老兵。
And I like to think my experience
我喜欢思考 我的经验
has led to some small skill in statecraft
导致了一些小技巧 治国之道
and underst... SANSA: Uncle?
然后… 叔叔？
Please sit.
请坐。
[SCOFFS]
（嘲笑）
[CLEARS THROAT SOFTLY]
[轻轻清嗓子]
[STUMBLES]
[蹒跚]
[SIGHS]
[叹息]
Well, we have to choose someone.
嗯，我们必须选择一个人。
Um, ahem...
嗯，呃…
Why just us?
为什么就是我们吗？
Um...
嗯。。。
We represent all the great houses,
我们代表 所有的大房子，
but whomever we choose,
但无论我们选择谁，
they won't just rule over lords and ladies.
他们不只是统治 大人女士们。
Maybe the decision about what's best for everyone
也许是关于 对每个人最好的是什么
should be left to...
应该留给……
well, everyone.
好吧，各位。
[ALL LAUGHING]
[都笑]
Maybe we should give the dogs a vote as well.
也许我们应该给狗 投票也是如此。
I'll ask my horse.
我去问我的马。
I suppose you want the crown.
我想你想要王冠。
Me?
我？
The Imp?
小鬼？
Half the people hate me for serving Daenerys,
一半的人恨我 为Daenerys服务，
the other half hate me for betraying her.
另一半恨我 因为背叛了她。
- Can't think of a worse choice. - Who, then?
-想不出更糟的选择。 -谁呢？
I've had nothing to do but think these past few weeks.
我除了思考什么都没做 过去几周。
About our bloody history.
关于我们的血腥历史。
About the mistakes we've made.
关于我们犯的错误。
What unites people?
什么使人团结？
Armies?
armies？
Gold?
黄金？
Flags?
旗？
Stories.
故事。
There's nothing in the world more powerful
世界上什么都没有 更强大
than a good story.
而不是一个好故事。
Nothing can stop it.
没有什么能阻止它。
No enemy can defeat it.
没有敌人能打败它。
And who has a better story...
谁有更好的故事…
than Bran the Broken?
比破碎的麦麸好吗？
The boy who fell from a high tower and lived.
摔倒的男孩 从一座高塔上住下来。
He knew he'd never walk again, so he learned to fly.
他知道他再也不会走路了， 所以他学会了飞行。
He crossed beyond the Wall,
他越过墙，
a crippled boy,
残疾的男孩，
and became the Three-Eyed Raven.
变成了三眼乌鸦。
He is our memory,
他是我们的记忆，
the keeper of all our stories.
我们所有故事的保管人。
The wars, weddings, births, massacres, famines.
战争，婚礼，出生， 屠杀，饥荒。
Our triumphs,
我们的胜利，
mm, our defeats,
嗯，我们的失败，
our past.
我们的过去。
Who better to lead us into the future?
谁能更好地领导我们？ 进入未来？
Bran has no interest in ruling and he can't father children.
布兰对执政没有兴趣 他不能当孩子的父亲。
Good.
很好。
Sons of kings can be cruel and stupid,
君王之子 可能是残忍和愚蠢的，
as you well know.
如你所知。
His will never torment us.
他永远不会折磨我们。
That is the wheel our queen wanted to break.
那是轮子 我们的女王想打破。
[♪♪♪]
[谚]
From now on, rulers will not be born.
从今以后， 统治者不会诞生。
They will be chosen on this spot
他们将被选中 在这一点上
by the lords and ladies of Westeros...
上议院和女士们 韦斯特罗斯…
to serve the realm.
为国家服务。
I know you don't want it.
我知道你不想要它。
I know you don't care about power.
我知道你不在乎 关于权力。
But I ask you now, if we choose you...
但我现在问你， 如果我们选择你…
will you wear the crown?
你要戴皇冠吗？
Will you lead the Seven Kingdoms to the best of your abilities
你能领导七国吗 尽你所能
from this day until your last day?
从这一天起 直到最后一天？
Why do you think I came all this way?
你为什么认为 我一路走来？
To Brandon of House Stark...
布兰登大学斯塔克的房子…………………
I say aye.
我说是啊。
[♪♪♪]
[谚]
SAMWELL: Aye.
SAMWELL： 是的。
MAN 1:
人1：
MAN 2: Aye.
人2： 是的。
YARA:
YARA：
MAN 3: Aye. MAN 4: Aye.
男3：是的。 男4：是的。
Aye.
是的。
I'm not sure I get a vote, but aye.
我不确定我有投票权， 但是，是的。
Aye.
是的。
I love you, little brother. I always will.
我爱你，小兄弟。 我永远都会。
You'll be a good king.
你会成为一个好国王的。
But tens of thousands of Northmen
但是数万 北方人
fell in the Great War defending all of Westeros.
在大战中倒下 保卫整个维斯特罗。
And those who survived have seen too much
还有那些幸存下来的人 看得太多了
and fought too hard ever to kneel again.
打得太厉害了 再次跪下。
The North will remain an independent kingdom,
北方将继续存在 独立的王国，
as it was for thousands of years.
因为它是 几千年来。
[♪♪♪]
[谚]
All hail Bran the Broken,
所有破碎的麦麸，
First of His Name,
他名字的第一个，
King of the Andals and the First Men,
安达尔之王 第一批人，
Lord of the Six Kingdoms and Protector of the Realm.
六国之王 以及王国的保护者。
ALL: All hail Bran the Broken!
所有： 所有的欢呼，布兰，破碎！
[♪♪♪]
[谚]
BRAN: Lord Tyrion...
麸皮： 提利昂勋爵…
you will be my Hand.
你将是我的手。
N...
N.…
No, Your Grace, I don't want it.
不，陛下， 我不想要它。
BRAN: And I don't want to be king.
麸皮： 我不想当国王。
I don't deserve it.
我不配。
I thought I was wise, but I wasn't.
我以为我很聪明， 但我没有。
I thought I knew what was right, but I didn't.
我以为我知道什么是对的，
Choose Ser Davos.
选择“达沃斯爵士”。
Choose anyone else.
选择其他人。
- I choose you. - You cannot.
我选你。 你不能。
Yes, I can.
是的，我能。
- I'm king. - This man is a criminal.
我是国王。 -这个人是罪犯。
- He deserves justice. - He just got it.
-他应该受到公正的对待。 -他刚拿到。
He's made many terrible mistakes.
他赚了很多 可怕的错误。
He's going to spend the rest of his life fixing them.
他要把剩下的花掉 他一生都在修理它们。
It is not enough.
这是不够的。
TYRION: Giving you to the Unsullied would start a war.
利昂：给你。 无垢者会发动战争。
Letting you walk free would start a war.
让你自由游走 会引发战争。
So our new king has chosen
所以我们的新国王选择了
to send you to the Night's Watch.
送你 到了晚上的时候。
There's still a Night's Watch?
还有一个晚上的表吗？
The world will always need a home
世界将永远 需要一个家
for bastards and broken men.
为混蛋和破碎的人。
[SIGHS]
[叹息]
You shall take no wife,
你不能娶任何妻子，
hold no lands,
不占有土地，
father no children.
父亲没有孩子。
The Unsullied wanted your head of course,
无垢者想要你的头 当然，
but Grey Worm has accepted the justice of a life sentence.
但是灰虫已经接受了 无期徒刑的公正性。
Sansa and Arya wanted you freed,
桑萨和雅利安想让你自由，
but they understand our new king needs to make peace.
但他们了解我们的新国王 需要和平。
No one is very happy.
没有人很高兴。
Which means it's a good compromise,
这意味着什么 这是一个很好的妥协，
I suppose.
我想。
Was it right?
是正确的吗？
What I did?
我做了什么？
What we did.
我们做了什么。
It doesn't feel right.
感觉不对劲。
Ask me again in 10 years.
十年后再问我一次。
I don't expect we'll ever see each other again.
我不奢望 我们再也见不到对方了。
I wouldn't be so sure.
我不太确定。
A few years as Hand of the King
几年的国王之手
would make anyone want to piss off the edge of the world.
会让任何人想 激怒了世界的边缘。
[♪♪♪]
[谚]
[HORSE NEIGHS]
[马嘶]
[MAN SHOUTS INDISTINCTLY]
[男人含糊不清地喊道]
[PEOPLE CHATTERING INDISTINCTLY]
[人们喋喋不休 隐晦地
[IN VALYRIAN]
[在]亚
[♪♪♪]
[谚]
SANSA: I wish there had been another way.
Sansa： 我希望有另一种方式。
Can you forgive me?
你能原谅我吗？
The North is free, thanks to you.
北方是自由的， 多亏了你。
But they lost their king.
但他们失去了国王。
Ned Stark's daughter will speak for them.
奈德·斯塔克的女儿 会为他们说话。
She's the best they could ask for.
她是最好的 他们可以要求。
[♪♪♪]
[谚]
You can come see me, you know, at Castle Black.
你可以来看我，你知道， 在布莱克城堡。
I can't.
我不能。
You think anyone will dare tell you women aren't allowed?
你认为任何人都会敢于 告诉你女人是不被允许的？
[CHUCKLES]
[Chuckles]
I'm not going back north.
我不回北方去。
Where are you going?
你要去哪里？
What's west of Westeros?
韦斯特罗斯西部是什么？
[CHUCKLES]
[Chuckles]
I don't know.
我不知道。
No one knows.
没有人知道。
It's where all the maps stop.
所有地图都停在这里。
That's where I'm going.
这就是我要去的地方。
You have your Needle?
你有针吗？
Right here.
就在这里。
[ARYA CRYING]
[艾莉亚哭]
Your Grace.
你的恩典。
I'm sorry I wasn't there when you needed me.
对不起，我不在那儿 当你需要我的时候。
You were exactly where you were supposed to be.
你就在那里 你应该是。
[SIGHS]
[叹息]
[♪♪♪]
[谚]
[DOOR OPENS]
[门打开]
[CLEARS THROAT]
[清喉咙]
That's not... Uh...
那不是…休斯敦大学。。。
What's this?
这是什么？
A Song of Ice and Fire.
冰与火之歌。
Archmaester Ebrose's history of the wars
埃布罗斯大学士的历史 战争中的
following the death of King Robert.
在死后 罗伯特王。
I helped him with the title.
我帮助他获得了这个头衔。
I suppose I come in for some heavy criticism.
我想我应该进来了 因为一些严厉的批评。
Oh, I wouldn't say that.
哦，我不会那么说的。
Oh, he's kind to me. Never would've guessed.
哦，他对我很好。 从来不会想到。
He's not kind?
他不善良？
- He... - He what?
-他… -他什么？
What does he say about me?
他说我什么？
I don't believe you're mentioned, ahem.
我不相信 你被提到了，嗯。
[DOOR OPENS]
[门打开]
[CLEARS THROAT]
[清喉咙]
- Your Grace.
-你的恩典。
We appear to be missing a Master of Whisperers.
我们好像失踪了 耳语大师。
And a Master of Laws.
以及法律硕士。
- And a Master of War. - Yes, Your Grace.
-一个战争大师。 -是的，陛下。
Suitable prospects will be brought to you
合适的前景 会带给你的
for an audience in the coming weeks.
为观众 在接下来的几周里。
And Drogon? Any word?
Drogon呢？有话吗？
He was last spotted flying east, toward...
他最后一次被发现向东飞行， 朝着…
The farther away, the better.
越远越好。
Perhaps I can find him.
也许我能找到他。
Do carry on with the rest.
其余的都要继续。
As you wish, Your Grace.
如你所愿，你的恩典。
Ser Podrick.
Ser Podrick。
[TYRION CLEARS THROAT]
[提利昂清嗓子]
We serve at your pleasure, King Bran the Broken,
我们乐意为您服务， 破碎的布兰国王，
ruler of the Six Kingdoms and Protector of the Realm.
六国统治者 以及王国的保护者。
- Long may he reign.
-愿他统治万岁。
Long may he reign.
愿他统治万岁。
That will improve.
这将有所改善。
I'm sure it will.
我相信会的。
[CLEARS THROAT, COUGHS]
[清喉咙，咳嗽]
Ser Bronn of the Blackwater,
黑水镇的布朗恩爵士，
Lord of Highgarden,
高加登勋爵，
Lord Paramount of the Reach
至高无上的领主
and Master of Coin,
和钱币大师，
would you say the crown's debt to you has been paid?
你能说国王的债务吗 给你钱了？
In full, my lord Hand.
我的主啊，我的全部。
Good.
很好。
Time to start incurring a new one.
开始发生的时间 一个新的。
We have hungry people to feed.
我们有饥饿的人要吃。
Can we expect some assistance in this regard?
我们能得到帮助吗 在这下的？
BRONN: Indeed we can.
波隆： 我们确实可以。
Lord Davos, we have an armada to rebuild and ports to repair.
达沃斯勋爵，我们有一个舰队 重建和修复端口。
We have. These projects will begin as soon as
我们有。这些项目 将尽快开始
the Master of Coin and Lord of Lofty Titles provides funding.
钱币大师 崇高的头衔提供资金。
The Master of Coin looks forward to helping the Master of Ships,
钱币大师向前看 帮助船长，
but first he has to ensure we're not wasting coin,
但首先他必须确保 我们不是在浪费硬币，
or soon there won't be no more coin.
或者很快就没有了 再也没有硬币了。
"Any more."
“再多。”
You Master of Grammar now too?
你现在太文理硕士吗？
Grandmaester, ahem,
大师，嗯，
it is my theory, based on my years of work
这是我的理论， 基于我多年的工作
on the Casterly Rock sewers,
在Casterly Rock下水道上，
that clean water leads to a healthier population.
干净的水 带来更健康的人口。
The Archmaester has done some research on this subject
大学士已经做了 关于这个问题的一些研究
and it turns out...
结果是…
The strong live and the weak don't.
坚强的生活 弱者不会。
Find the best builders and set them to the task.
找到最好的建设者 把他们安排到任务上。
BRONN: Oh, speaking of builders, all the best brothels burned down.
布朗恩：哦，说到建筑工人， 所有最好的妓院都被烧毁了。
The Master of Coin is willing to fund reconstruction.
钱币大师愿意 为重建提供资金。
SAMWELL: Uh... the Archmaester is less than enthusiastic
SAMWELL：嗯… 大学士不太热情
about the salutary effects of brothels.
关于有益效果 妓院的
BRONN: Well, I imagine he isn't using them properly.
BRONN：嗯， 我想他没有正确使用它们。
BRIENNE: I think we can all agree that ships
布莱恩： 我想我们都同意船
take precedence over brothels.
优先于妓院。
BRONN: I think that's a very presumptuous statement.
波隆： 我认为这是一个非常傲慢的说法。
TYRION: I once brought a jackass
利昂： 我有一次带了个蠢货
and a honeycomb into a brothel.
一个蜂巢进入妓院。
[WIND WHISTLING]
[吹口哨]
[HORN SOUNDING]
[喇叭测深]
[INHALES AND EXHALES HEAVILY]
[吸气和呼气剧烈]
[♪♪♪]
[谚]
[GHOST WHINES]
[鬼魂哀鸣]
MAN: The Queen in the North!
男人： 女王在北。
ALL [CHANTING]:
所有[吟唱]：
[WIND WHISTLING]
[吹口哨]
[PEOPLE CHATTERING INDISTINCTLY]
[人们喋喋不休 隐晦地
[♪♪♪]
[谚]
[CHOIR VOCALIZING]
[合唱团演唱]